Erikas Taroza

PROFILE

I am an experienced software developer with a diverse set of skills including Flutter/Dart, web development, Git, and Linux. My journey in software development is marked by my drive to constantly grow my skills and my commitment to excellence. I am also an active contributor to the open-source community. I maintain my own projects as well as help fix various bugs in other open-source projects. These contributions are proof of my skills and also showcase my dedication to supporting fellow developers.

EXPERIENCE

January 2023 - Present

Full Stack Developer, IDMSRTV (Startup)

- · Implemented core functionality of product
- · Drove strategy for website development
- Identified and implemented modern technologies to get the beta website to market faster
- Collaborated with cross functional team leaders to define project scope and timelines
- Rewrote WordPress website with improved styling and functionality
- · Frameworks/languages used
 - Angular
 - Java (Android app)
 - Vue
 - Rust
 - 。 PHP
 - WordPress

October 2022 - December 2022

Intern Web Developer, Deidis (Startup)

- Developed widget to provide clients an easy way to capture leads
- React (frontend)
- NodeJS (backend)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Google Cloud Certified

After spending 1 month learning Google Cloud, I am now certified as an Associate Cloud Engineer.

See Certificate

PROJECTS

October 2022 - Present

simple_audio

- · A simple cross-platform solution for playing audio in Flutter
- Rust
- · Open source

May 2022 - Present

BitBeat

- · Music streaming app with no ads
- Flutter (frontend)
- · Rust (backend)
- · Vue (backend forms)
- Docker

December 2020 - Present

Open Source

Contributing to open source projects by fixing issues, adding new features, or creating my own open source projects.

See my work here: https://github.com/erikas-taroza

EDUCATION

July 2019 - January 2023

Laurel Springs School

High School

- 3.75 GPA (3.90 weighted)
- AP Computer Science (4/5 on AP exam)

July 2016 - Present

Self-Taught

I taught myself everything I know about programming.

SKILLS

Git

- · Critical Thinking
- Computers and Technology
- Ability to Learn

Research

- · Problem Solving
- Linux